to
live welcome brothers and sisters to
another Israel of God Wednesday night
question and answer will we open up with
the Ten Commandments that God commanded
the world to keep brother
tanzel and God spake all these words
saying I am the Lord thy God which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt
out of the house of bondage thou to have
no other gods before me thou not make
unto thee any Graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the Earth
thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them for I the Lord thy God am
a jealous God visiting the iniquities of
the fathers upon the children unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me and showing Mercy unto thousands
of them that love me and keep my
Commandments thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain
for the Lord will not hold him Guiltless
that take up his name in vain remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy six days
shall thou LA and do all thy work but
the seven day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God in it thou shall not do any work
thou no thy son no th daughter thy man
servant nor that maid servant no thy
cattle no th stranger that is within thy
gates for six days the Lord made Heaven
and Earth the sea and all all that in
them is and rested the seventh day
wherefor the Lord bless the Sabbath day
and hollowed it honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God give
thee thou shall not kill thou shall not
commit adultery thou sh not steal thou
not bear false witness against thy
neighbor thou not cover thy neighbor's
house thou not cover that neighbor's
wife nor his man's servant nor his maid
servant no his Ox nor asked nor anything
that is thy neighbors we read Exodus 21
through1 17 and may the Lord have a
blessing to the reading of his words in
Jesus name we pray amen
amen so here on question and answer you
can ask us a question and we will answer
it according to the King James Bible and
if we cannot find an answer we will seek
further counsel to bring you an answer
at a latter time and keep in mind all
vague questions will not be answered and
all long scripture questions will not be
answered for time sake but we may point
you in the direction of a CD or dvd that
you can purchase by calling the office
so for time sake we ask that you be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible
nor the Bibles will will be acknowledged
on this program this is a live stream so
if you have any questions you can submit
them at this time let me introduce you
to the family that will take part on the
panel this evening we got brother
tanzel good evening we got brother
Jerome RA in peace we got sister
Deborah good
evening we got the guest call and we got
sister Casey and I am brother Dre and
what is our first question of the
evening sister de all right there are
several held over questions that will be
answered first before getting into
tonight's Q&A Gloria Simon asks is there
anywhere in the Bible about donating
your organs can you or can't you
yeah um sister they there's nothing that
I read in the scriptures that says you
can I cannot donate your organs there's
nothing in the Bible against it so uh
there are a lot of people that are alive
today because of organ don
donation uh
unfortunately organ harvesting exist as
well but in terms of of your question is
there something against it in the Bible
no there is not and I hope that that
answers your question and we'll move on
to the
next yes next one Malik shur asked in
Matthew 1 verse 19 when Joseph was
minded to put Mary away privately was he
thinking about sending her away possibly
to another
city we're going to ask brother Jerome
to answer that question brother
Jerome no that's not what he was
thinking he wasn't thinking about
sending her away to another city let's
go read and find out what he was doing
uh let's go to that first chapter
Matthews chapter one verse 19 when you
get it go ahead and read then Joseph her
husband being a just man and I willing
to make her a public example was minded
to put her away
privately okay so uh it said in the
verse that Joseph was her husband okay
so they were married but you know he
thought that she had slept with another
man because she was found with child and
it was it wasn't by him so he was going
to put her away privately meaning that
he was going to
absorb the the
marriage okay or divorce so to speak
okay so let's let go read Verse 18 and
19 ver now the birth of Jesus Christ was
on this wise when as his mother Mary was
exposed to Joseph before they came
together she was FR with child of the
Holy
Ghost then Joseph her husband being a
just man and not willing to make her a
public example was minding to put her
away
privately that's that's that's all I got
on he he was just going to uh absolve
the marriage and put her away privately
he didn't want to make a public display
about what he thought and that was that
she had slept with a another man when in
fact she did that's all I got
on thank you brother Jerome for that
answer sister Deborah we'll move on to
the next question all right uh Zion ass
in sticking with the same book and uh
chap
Zion asked in Matthew 1 verse 20 was
Joseph thinking or sleeping first it
said he thought on these things then
verse 24 is said he was raised from
sleep yes we'll ask brother Jerome to
answer that question as well brother
Jerome okay um T read that verse
20 but while he thought on these things
behold the angel of the Lord appeared
unto him in a dream saying Joseph thou
son of David fear not to take unto thee
Mary thy wife for that which is
conceived in her is of the Holy
Ghost okay so yeah Joseph he he he was
thinking about the whole situation
regarding Mary and her being found with
child okay but at some point in time you
know he did fall asleep and while he
fell asleep then the angel uh appeared
to him and communicated with him by
dream okay so
uh read read that verse 20 again and
verse
21 but while he thought on these things
behold the angel of the Lord appeared
unto him in a dream saying Joseph thou
son of David Fe not to take unto thee
Mary thy wife for that which is
conceived in her is of the Holy Ghost
uhhuh and she shall bring forth a son
and thou shall call his name Jesus he
shall save his people from their
sins okay so this is what the uh Angel
was communicating to Joseph
in a dream after he had fell asleep okay
but then he he he woke from that sleep
okay so skip down and read verse
24 then Joseph being raised from sleep
did as the angel of the Lord had bitten
him and took unto him his wife yeah cuz
he let him know no she didn't deal with
another man this is of the Holy Ghost
okay he gonna be called a child or the
Son of God okay that's all I got on it
right Jerome and it said in verse 25 and
he knew her not till she brought forth
her firstborn
son he did not know her before then
that's right okay we that that helps
we'll move on to the next question
sister Deborah yes next question
Valencia says can you explain Exodus
34: 19 and 20
yes we're going to ask the guest caller
to answer that question guest
caller goad and read
it Exodus 34 vers 19 and
20 all that openeth the Matrix is mine
and every first thing among thy cattle
whether ox or sheep that is male but the
first thing of an as thou shall redeem
with the lamb and if thou redeem him not
then shall thou break his neck all the
firstborn of thy Sons thou sh redeem and
None Shall appear before me
empty all they saying is that all the uh
the firstborn and the Israel would be
offered up to the Lord they wouldn't be
killed you know they just dedicate them
to the Lord and then all the firstborn
of the animals you know like ox and
stuff like that you you uh uh uh uh
sacrifice it to the Lord and the first
born of if a first born of an ass being
it as unclean uh animal then you could
redeem him in other words sacrifice an a
lamb a a before him or either if you
don't have a clean animal then you have
to break the ass's neck because the Lord
is it and the reason the Lord did all
that is because he killed the firstborn
in Egypt
so God being a fair God he took the
first born from among Israel but he just
didn't kill them he said but they
his that's all I have to
say thank you for that guest caller we
hope that that helps and we'll move on
sister Deborah to our next
question yes moving on Shon Ro asks who
are the 4 and 20 elders in Revelation
4 let's go to Revelation 4 and we're
going to read verse 4 Revelation 4 and
4 when you get it go ahead read verse
one and then read verse four
bro after this I looked and behold a
door was open in heaven and the first
voice which I heard was as it were of a
trumpet talking with me which said said
come up hither and I will show thee
things which must be Hereafter so these
things are to be Hereafter which is for
a time to come skip down to verse four
go
ahead and round about The Throne were
four and 20 seats and upon the seats I
saw four and 20 Elders sitting clothed
and white raining and they had on their
heads crowns of gold so these Elders
they had they were clothed and right
Raymond and they had crowns of gold on
their head now let's go take a look at
them let's go to First
Chronicles the 24th chapter 1 Chronicles
24 1 Chronicles
24 and
uh let's pick it up at verse
one go ahead and read brother when you
get now these are the divisions of the
sons of Aaron the sons of Aaron naab and
Abu Eleazar and
ethar bab and Abu died before their
father and had no children therefore
elazi and ethar executed the priest's
office go ahead and David distribute
them both zadok of the sons of Eleazar
and a himc of the sons of ethar
according to their offers and their
service right so you see here the sons
of of descendants of Aaron the priests
the sons of Eleazar and the sons of
ithamar right go ahead read verse
four and there were more Chief men found
of the sons of Eleazar then of the sons
of ethar and thus were they
divided among the sons of Eleazar there
were 16 Chief men of the House of their
father and eight among the sons of ethar
according to the house of their fathers
so you got 16 Chief men of the sons of
Eleazar and eight of the sons of ithamar
and 16 and 8 is
24 Now read verse seven
brother now the first L came forth jeho
the son of
Jedediah the the third to Haram the
fourth to seim and the fifth to m m the
six
toan we not gonna read all these names
so we'll just go right down to it Verse
18 and the three and 20th of Delia the
fourth and 20th to meiah and these were
the or The Ordering of them in their
service to come into the house of the
Lord according to their manner under
Aaron their father as the Lord God of
Israel had commanded him this is what
their office is to do and they will be
performing this office during the
Thousand-Year Millennial period as the
priest doing what they do and it it
tells you here in verse 18 the 24th is
uh the 4 and 20th is Messiah so I hope
that that helps if anybody would like to
add with that we'll move on sister
Dev yes Dorothy Griff on Guess
call I just want to say quickly so
they'll be clear these 24 Elders are the
24 sons of Aaron and they will not be
around the throne until Jesus come
because that throne in in uh uh uh
Revelation 4 chapter the Throne of
Jesus
absolutely absolutely they going to rule
because Paul told you that the world
that come is not will not be subject to
Angels it's going to be subject to us
that makes that first 20 that first
resurrection that's all I have to say
that's right and and and addition to
that you got when the apostles came they
say hey we didn't sacrifice all what
shall we have and he said hey when I
come into my kingdom you will sit on
throne
judging the 12 tribes of
Israel all this ties
in but uh we'll move on sister Deborah
next question next question Dorothy
Griffith asks where does it say in the
scripture that people will be taught the
word so they can be saved on that great
day we're going to ask the guest caller
to answer that question guest caller
you know you
see what's the question
again all right the question again
was where does it say in the scripture
that people will be taught the word so
they can be saved on that great
day well I can show you where the
scripture say you're going to be judged
according to what's taught in this
Bible let's go into Revelation 20th
chapter actually actually was that your
question
Jerome
um um it's fine um
um okay okay
um I actually haven't read in the Bible
where it actually read that way um that
you got it formulated in the question
but I was looking that St John chapter 6
verse 44 and 45 and that that's more
closer to what I think you're saying in
this question so let's go take a look at
that St John chapter 6 verse 44 and 45
let you get it go ahead and read no man
can come to me except the Father which
have sent me draw him and I will raise
him up at the last day now when you when
you refer to the great day in this
question this last day is the coming of
the
Lord okay but go ahead keep reading it
is written in the prophets and they
shall be all taught of God and every man
therefore that have heard and have
learned of the father cometh unto me
yeah so the whole earth going to be full
of knowledge of the Lord when he come
when he come he gonna teach he gonna
teach man on this
Earth You know but so that's the only
one I think of you might be referring to
that's all I got
on thank you for that brother Jerome
sister Deborah will move on to the next
question all right uh Stephen googus
asks what is the corner of a man's beard
also what is rounding the corners of
your head and uh Leviticus 19 verse 27
is given and they want to know and he
wants to know does this law still apply
today um
for what it's dealing with absolutely so
but let's go to that Leviticus 19 let's
go to Leviticus
19 and we're g to pick it up at verse 27
Leviticus 19 27 and 28 brother tanzel
read that when you get
it ye shall not round the corners of
your heat neither shall thou Mar the
corners of thy
beard you should not make any cuting in
your flesh for the dead nor print any
marks upon you I am the Lord now this is
what a lot of times they were doing for
the dead back then right that's what
they did now let's go right over to
Leviticus
21 and read verse one and then we'll go
over to verse 5 Leviticus 21 read verse
one and then skip down to verse
five go ahead and the Lord said unto
Moses speaking to the priest the sons of
Aaron and say unto them there shall none
be defiled for the dead among his people
now he's speaking to the priest here
he's saying the sons of Aaron the priest
here None Shall defile themselves for
the dead among his people
right skip down to verse five brother
they should not make bonness upon their
head neither shall they shave off the
corners of their beard nor make any
cuting in their flesh so this is for the
dead that they did these things and you
can read about that also in in Isaiah 15
1 and2 Jeremiah 165 and 6 but we just
going to go to one other place let's go
to Deuteronomy 14 and we're gonna read
verse one Deuteronomy 14 and verse one
go ahead brother when you get
it ye are the children of the Lord your
God you should not cut yourselves nor
make any B between your eyes for the
dead for Thou Are Holy people unto the
Lord thy God and the Lord have chosen
thee To Be A peculiar people unto
himself above all the nations that upon
the Earth so this this thing that they
were doing the corners of they bed and
all that stuff it was for the dead this
is why they did right and and if you
doing it for the dead don't do
it it's just that simple other than that
I don't see I I haven't read nothing
else about it now uh that's all I got on
that question I hope it helps sister
Deborah next
question all right uh leaping lamb asked
in Genesis 5 verse 32 were sham ham and
J fat
triplets we're gonna ask the guest
caller was shim ham and jath triplets
guest
caller no they wasn't this will let you
know that they
wasn't go to
Genesis 10 chapter and read verse
21 Genesis 10 and
21 uhhuh 10 and
21 unto shim also the father of all the
children of
Eber the brother of japheth the Elder
even to him were children
born now right there let you know that
they Wen the same age okay the brother
of
Jaan the
Elder if he got an elder that mean that
they they would not they would not
triplets that's all they have to
say all right thank you for that answer
sister Deborah time
check yes the time is
7:55 uh tomorrow Williams asks the
children that God has chosen as his
Saints will they return with Jesus as an
adult in his second coming
guest caller the the
children that's chosen and go ahead
n there is no scripture that states
that I would assume that they will be
grown but there's nothing written that
states that so I can't give you an
answer all
right all right sister Deborah next
question yes a Thomas asked how does iog
as a state and federal entity refute
that the church is required to perform
samex
marriages um the
question about that let me let me answer
that yes call how how does the iog as a
state and federal uh entity we the iog
is not a state of federal
entity Israeli God is the Church of God
got nothing to do with the state of the
federal so wherever you get your
information from is
erroneous that's all we need to answer
on that yes sir thank you for that guest
calling sister Deborah we're going to
the next
question hey Thomas also asked in 1
Samuel 16
verse2 David was Ruddy what is Ruddy
Esau was Ruddy is this the
same yes
call let's go and and see what the Bible
say about Esau
okay let's go into what was that 1st
Samuel 16 and
12 yes let's read go and read
it and he said and brought him in now he
was Ruddy and and with all of a
beautiful countenance and goodly to look
to and the Lord said arise anoint him
for this is
he okay now he said he was ready there
now let's go and look at how Esau was
described let's go into uh uh
um what is I think it's uh Exodus the
15th
chapter Exodus 25 some kind of way I
uh overl at Exodus
25 where and let's see where uh Esau and
Jacob was Bor Genesis
25 Genesis
get right down Genesis 25 and get right
down to
it started uh you probably hit it hit it
at 20
23 or 24
okay okay 2024 go ahead and read it when
you get there and when her days to be
delivered were fulfilled behold there
were twins in her womb and the first
came out red all over like a hairy
garment and they called his name
Esau now that didn't say ready did no
red and rdy two different things rdy is
a reddish
[Music]
brown yes
sir that's two different colors all
together that's all I have to say about
that thank you for that guest caller we
hope that that answered your question
and we will move on to the next question
sister
Deborah yes noris T says I wanted to
know about
words I wanted to know whose words
scared Saul Samuels or a familiar Spirit
what did the Bible
say I'm gonna ask brother Jerome to
answer that question brother
Jerome well lord said with all your
getting getting understanding um the
Bible did
say Samuel not because it was actually
Samuel it was because Saul
perceived it was Samuel it was actually
a familiar spirit and a familiar Spirit
by the
request of Saul was to raise Samuel up
that familiar Spirit ain't raising
Samuel up cuz not going to go against
what the Lord
wanted so Sam Samuel wasn't raised from
the
dead to talk to
anybody and he
died in the 25th chapter okay so it was
a familiar
spirit that was communicating
through this
witch Witcher indor
and Samuel was just perceiving uh uh
Saul was just perceiving that it was
Samuel it was not okay uh now let I want
to read Ecclesiastes 9 and I want to
read job because the dead know not
anything they don't have no more portion
of anything done under the
sun okay so let's go read that
Ecclesiastes 9 we also going to do that
first Chronicles too let you know that
Samuel I'm sorry SA
communicated with that familiar Spirit
and the Lord was so displeased when he
said for that you going to die for that
okay but uh let's do Ecclesiastes 9 and
read verse four and five and then we're
going to do Job chapter
14 when you get it go ahead and read for
to him that is joined to all the living
there is hope for a living dog is better
than a dead
lion for the living know that they shall
die but the dead know not anything
neither have they any more reward for
the memory of them is
forgotten okay now we gonna do joob
14 and we going to read verse 14 then we
going to skip
up Job 14 and4 then we going to skip
up if a man die shall he live again
all the days of my appointed time will I
wait till my change
come and that's what job let you know so
Samuel gonna have to wait for he
get raised up right okay now read verse
12 and
13 so man lith down and riseth not till
the heavens be no more they shall not
awake nor be raised out of their
sleep so that is not raised in Samuel
up okay he not going to do it all
right and that famili spirit with
deceiving not only the witch indor with
deceiving Samuel too okay he even
mentioned that as Samuel okay so let's
go to that uh 1 Chronicles now and read
verse 10 uh chapter 10 verse
13 First Chronicles
chapter
10 verse verse 13 verse 13
yeah so Saul died for his transgression
which he committed against the Lord even
against the word of the Lord which he
kept not and also for asking counsel of
one that had a familiar Spirit to
inquire of it so the inquire of the
familiar spirit and you can read all
through that chapter 28 that that's what
they was both dealing with that famili
Spirit which is a fallen angel okay now
one other point
[Music]
um uh
Samuel being dead when he was alive he
didn't tell
Saul that him and his sons were going to
be
killed in the war against the
Philistines Samuel had died before he
even told before before even knowing
that
he was going to be going to war against
the Philistines and him and his sons
were going to be killed Samuel was
already dead before that even took
place okay so that's something else keep
in mind that's all I got on here if
anybody want to add they
can thank you brother Jerome we help
that we hope that that helped your
question we hope you got an answer for
that and uh we will move on to the next
question sister Deborah
yes read the Bible daily as for you to
explain Revelations 2 verses four and
five what is thy first
love so let's go to that Revelations 2
and we're going to uh start at verse two
and read down into
four
uh go ahead my brother when you get it
Revelations 2 and two
I Know Thy works and thy labor and thy
patient and how thou canest not bear
them which are evil and thou has tried
them which say they are Apostles and are
not and them liar he said I know your
works I know your works and your labor
and your patience and you can't bear
them which are
evil and you tried those that say they
are Apostles and are not and you found
them to be
Liars go ahead verse
three and has born and has patience and
for my name's sake has Labb and has not
fainted nevertheless I have somewh
against thee because thou H has left
that first love and that first love is
all these things we reading about right
here that word being in you and has born
and has patience and for my name sake
have labored and not fainted
nevertheless I have somewhat against
thee because you left your first love
verse five brother go ahead remember
therefore from when thou are fallen and
repent and do the first works or else I
will come unto thee quickly and will
remove thy Candlestick out of his place
except thou repent so turn away from
what you were doing and do that which
was right to begin with now let's go to
one other place let's go to Deuteronomy
6 Deuteronomy 6 and we going to read
Verses 4 to
six go ahead when you get it
Tel hereo Israel the Lord our God is one
Lord and thou sh love the Lord thy God
with all thine heart and with all thy
soul and with all thy might
and these words which I commanded thee
this day shall be in thy heart okay
that's enough now he said these he said
Thou shalt love the Lord with all thy
heart and with all thy soul and with all
thy
might this is that first love that word
being in you and turning back to it is
what was said to them in Ephesus in that
revelation
uh the second chapter I hope that that
helps we'll move on to the next question
sister
Deborah yes uh nesa says in First
Corinthians 11 vers 3 through six my
husband said God would not hear any of
my prayers unless I go through him he
says God doesn't deal with any women
with hus husbands is this
true we're going to ask the guest caller
to answer that question 1 Corinthians 11
verses
3-6 go read it let's see what it
say but I will have you know that the
head of every man is Christ and the head
of the woman is the man and the head of
Christ is
God every man praying or prophesying
having his head covered dishonor is he
but every woman that pray or prophesieth
with her head uncovered dishonor her
head for that is even all one as if she
was
shaved now I'm looking at this I didn't
see nowhere what it said that a woman
have to go through her husband to get to
God let me show you what the Bible said
when it come to
Salvation let's go to Philippians the 2
chapter and read verse 12
Philippians 2
and12 wherefore my beloved as ye have
always obeyed not as in my presence only
but now much more in my absence work out
your own salvation with fear and
trembling now your own mean that you are
responsible for your salvation isn't
that correct
mm not to let your husband work out your
own Salvation let's go into Ezekiel the
14th
chapter and we're going to read from 12
to
21 read it when you get
there the word of the Lord came again to
me saying son of man when the land sinth
Against Me by trespassing grievously
then will I stretch out my hand upon it
and will break the staff of the bread
thereof and will send famine upon it and
will cut off man and Beast from
it though these three men Noah Daniel
and Joel were in it they shall deliver
but their own Souls by their
righteousness sayth the Lord God and if
I cause no Beast to pass through the
land and they spoil it so that it be
desolate that no man may pass through
because of the Beast though these three
men were in it as I live say the Lord
God they shall deliver neither son nor
daughters they only shall be delivered
but the land shall be
desolate or if I bring sword upon the
land and say sword go through the land
so that I cut off man and Beast from it
though these three men were in it as I
live sayth the Lord God they shall
deliver neither son nor daughters but
they only shall be delivered
themselves so now this let us know that
each individual could only deliver them
themselves you can't deliver your son
you can't deliver your daughter and you
can't deliver your wife
right was that that was that
21 that was now we stopped at uh in
18 go ahead get to 21 or if I send a
pestilent into the land and pour out my
Fury upon it in blood to cut off from it
man in Beast though Noah Daniel and Joel
were in it as I live say the Lord God
they shall deliver neither son nor
daughter they shall be deliver their own
Souls by their
righteousness huh finish goad that's it
that was end of
20 go
ahead thus said the Lord God how much
more when I send my foro judgment upon
Jerusalem The Sword and the famine and
the noan Beast and the pestilence to cut
off from it man and
Beast so now these guys can only deliver
himself and all the and and these guys
had wives and these was righteous men
but they could deliver the the sons the
daughters the wife nobody else but
themselves by their own righteousness
now let's go to acts the 2 chapter and
read verse
4 yes
sir Acts 2 and
[Music]
40 and with many other words did he
testify and exhort saying save
yourselves from this unto
generation so so who did say who who did
he say say yourself yourself
because you're the only one that can
save
yourself but I will say one thing and
the
sistered I don't care who it is if they
go Accord if they go contrary to the
word of
God you don't follow not even your
husband I'm going to give you a good
example cuz he might be a foolish
husband let's go into acts the 5th
chapter and this is when the apostles
all all that pled he guys all that PL to
S Apostles of land and donated to the
church all the money so we got a guy
that's going to be real smart and I'm
pretty
sure he sold the idea to his wife too
acts five and we're going to read from
one start at verse one from 1 to
five one to yeah go ahead and read it
but a certain man named anias was
Safari's wife sold a possession
and kept back part of the price his wife
also being privy to it and brought a
certain part and laid it at the apostles
feet but Peter said and Ani why have
Satan filled their heart to lie to the
Holy Ghost and to keep back part of the
price of the land while it remain it was
it not that own and after it was sold
was it not th own power so why hast thou
conceed this thing in thy heart thou has
not lied unto men but unto God
and ananas hearing these words fell down
and gave up The Ghost and great fear
came on all them that heard these
things okay so now this man thought
himself ly he going to lie to God he
going to sell some property and hold
back part of the money and God kill him
on the spot keep
reading and the young men arose grounded
him up and carried him out and buried
him and it was about the space three
hours after when his wife not knowing
what was done came in and Peter answered
unto her but tell me whether you sold
the land for so much and she said yeah
for so much then Peter said unto her how
is it that ye have agreed together to
tempt the spirit of the Lord behold the
feet of them which have buried thy
husband are at the door and shall carry
thee out then fell she down straight way
at his feet and yielded up The Ghost and
the young man came in and found her dead
and carrying her forth buried her by her
husband so now if your husband telling
you that you have to go through
him that is totally contrary to the word
of God totally
contrary and if he should lead you wrong
and you follow him God going to kill him
and you you better pay attention to what
the book said work out your own
salvation with fear and trembling and
you deliver yourself because the only
one you can deliver is you and the only
one that your husband can deliver is him
and if he tell you this kind of
information you better sure enough be
suspect to him because look like you
going to end up falling down to and
being carried out and buried that's all
I got to
say thank you for that answer guest
caller excellent answer
sister Deborah time
check yes the time is
8:17 and we are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday August the 14
2024 Nicholas toer
asks what race is
Esau Hebrew we're gonna ask brother
Jerome to answer that question brother
Jerome
yeah we get this question all the time
Esau is Hebrew he not a gentile he the
twin brother of Jacob whose name was
changed to Israel but let's go and look
at the
Chronicles go to 1 Chronicles chapter
1 and we going to trace him all the way
down from
Shem 1 Chronicles chap 1 pick it up at
I didn't say he was a Hebrew Israelite
but he's still Hebrew because Abraham is
a father of many nations the midianites
are Hebrews but they're not Israelites
you know but go ahead and pick it up at
that
24 Shem or faad
Sheila Eber pag R
rayu and serug n nahor and
trra abam the same as Abraham so we see
that Abraham traced down from shim skip
down and read verse did you read verse
28 read that the sons of Abraham Isaac
and ishmail Skip down to verse
34 and Abraham begat Isaac the sons of
Isaac Esau and Israel so Esau is
mentioned right next to Israel because
they twin brothers we read that in not
too long ago I think in Genesis uh
chapter
25 okay so he's Hebrew a Hebrew
Edomite right that's all I
got that's what it calls him in Genesis
36 he is an Edomite 8 and N yeah and and
Deuteronomy 23 it say don't upo an
Edomite because he is thy brother yes
sir thank you for that brother Jerome
sister Deborah we're going to move on to
the next question yes moving on excuse
me Ben F says when Herod was appointed
King was the temple in Jerusalem shared
by descendants of Jacob and Esau before
Rome destroyed it in 70 AD since Herod
was a descendant of Esau
we're going to ask the guest caller to
answer that question guest
caller yeah well well Esau some of
was in Jerusalem but actually
were next to Jerusalem Southern
Jerusalem which is called anab and and
it was named
aduma but whether they Shar the temple
or not I don't know but I know a lot of
uh was running with the
Pharisees so they were the on that
trying to trap Jesus let's go into
Matthews 22nd chapter read verses 15 and
16 was that Matthew
yes 15 and
16 then went the Pharisees and took
counsel how they might entangle him in
his talk
and they sent out unto him their
disciples with the herodian saying
Master now we know that thou art true
and teachest the way of God in truth
neither carest thou for any man for thy
regard is not the pur of
man who did he send
out who did they send
out they sent out their disciples with
the herodians
that's right with the the the the uh uh
uh their disciples and herodian the
herodians are right
herodians those are the ones that uh uh
was called that after Herod okay so they
was there questioning Jesus together
they they moved as a unit now let's go
into Mark the 3 chapter and read verse
six mark
and verse
6 M and the Pharisees went forth and
straightway took counsel with the
herodians against him how they might
destroy
him now see they were there they were
there together they studed
together so they might as well you know
and they shared Jerusalem together even
though the had the had the
little had Southern Jerusalem which they
named aduma but the Pharisees and the
herodians that is the Edomite they ran
together and they was both trying to
squeeze Jesus
together that's all I have to say about
that thank you for that answer guest
caller we're gonna move on sister
Deborah next question yes he Al his
other question was is there a reason as
to why Herod had the inclination to kill
all male children or baby Jesus when
there hadn't been a prophet in about 400
years since
Nehemiah guess
caller first thing let me make a
correction last prophet was John the
Baptist Bible uh uh uh uh he was
however the reason we going to read it
to you let's go to Matthew the 2
chapter yes sir
and read verses 1 through3 first then
we're going to skip
down Matthew 2
1-3 now when Jesus was born in Bethlehem
of Judea in the days of Herod the king
behold there came wise men from the East
to
Jerusalem saying where is he that is
born King of the Jews we have seen his
star in the east and I come to worship
Him and when Herod the king had heard
these things he was struggled and all
Jerusalem with
him okay so let's see what he did with
these wise men skip down and read seven
and
eight then Herod when he had privately
called the wise men and inquired of them
diligently what time the star appeared
and he sent them to Bethlehem and said
go and search diligently for the young
child and when he had found him bring me
word again that I may come and worship
him
also okay let's see what the wise men
what happened with the wise men skip
down to verse 16 no did we read verse 12
for verse
12 verse 12 and being warned of God in a
dream that they should not return to
Heron they departed into their own
country another
way yes sir skip down to verse
16 then Herod when he saw that he was
mocked of the wise men was exceeding
Rock and sent forth and slew all the
children that were in Bethlehem and in
all the coast thereof from two years old
and under according to the time which he
had diligently inquired of the wise
men now Herod kill him
because they trying to catch Jesus
because it was said Jesus was the king
of the Jews and Herod was the appointed
King of the Jews by the Romans so that
was herod's Mo gu killed his one of his
wife CU he thought she was trying to
take over kill some of his son because
he thought he was trying to take over
his throne you going and read up on
Herod so when Jesus came along they say
he is the king of the Jews here us uhuh
I'm the king what I'm going to do is I'm
going to kill him that's the reason is
that he killed all the wise men all the
babies from the time that he inquired of
the wise men until the present time
trying to catch Jesus because he was
King and he wasn't going to let nobody
else nobody take his
throne that's all I have to
say thank you for that answer guest
caller sister Deborah we're going to
move on to our next
question yes uh these next three
questions are asked by dot Martin she
says can you explain Genesis 6 verse 11
and 12 is it talking about the actual
Earth not
man let's go to that Genesis 6 and we'll
read verses 11 through
13 and open it to the
panel go ahead brother and read it when
you get
there the Earth also was corrupt before
God and the Earth was filled with
violence and God looked upon the Earth
and behold it was corrupt for All Flesh
had corrupted his way upon the Earth and
God said unto Noah the end of All Flesh
has come before me for the Earth is
filled with violence through them and
behold I will destroy them with the
Earth notice it said that the people
said the end of all fleshes come before
me because it's filled with violence
through them right the people was the
ones that were corrupt and if you bagged
up and and read it from the beginning
you would see that the thoughts of their
heart were continuously
[Music]
evil and it repented the Lord that he
had made the Earth because man's
thoughts were only evil contention
is not talking about the Earth it's
talking about the people in the Earth
right
okay sister Deborah we'll move on to the
next question right her next question
she says the people of
today that are extremely tall like 7
foot and up are they Giants or were the
Giants in Genesis 6 verse4
taller brother Tel we gonna read that
Genesis 6 and4 and we'll open it up to
the
pat go ahead and read it when you get
it now there were giants in the earth in
those days and also after that and when
the sons of God came in unto the
daughters of men and they bear children
to them the same became Mighty Men which
were of old men of renown
Renown open to the
panel well the first thing it didn't say
that these Giants
come uh that these Giants come from
between the uh uh sons of God and the
daughters of men which is the sons of uh
of uh uh
uh Adam and
Zat and the daughters was uh um um C's
daughters but there was Giants on this
side of the fluid too let's go into 1st
Samuel 17th chapter and read verse
4 1 Samuel 17 and verse
four
uhhuh all right brother
T and there went out Champion out of the
camp of the Philistines named Goliath of
G whose height was six cubers in the
span now six cub in a span that is uh uh
I look that up that is 9t 9 in tall and
it called him a giant and he wasn't the
only one let's go to second Samuel 21st
chapter read from verse 15 to 22
when you get there what was that
again second second Samuel 21 ver 15-
22 2 Samuel 21 vers 15-
22 21
okay start at verse 15 yes sir over the
Philistines had yet War again with
Israel and David went down and fought
against the Philistines and David waxed
faint and is by bonab which was of the
sons of the giant the weight whose spear
weighed 300 shekles of brass and weight
and he being GED with a new sword
thought to have slain
David but go ahead but abashi the son of
zeru secured him and smoked the
Philistine and killed him then the man
of David swear unto him saying thou
shall go no more out with us to battle
thou sh quench not the light of Israel
and it came to pass after this that
there was again a battle with the
Philistine of
God then
cesiah the Shu the the shite slew sa
which was of the sons of the Giant and
there was again a Battle of God with the
Philistines for El Han Hanan the son of
Jed origin of bethle bethlehemite slew
the brother of Goliath the gitite the
staff of whose spear was like a weava be
and there was yet a battle in G where
there was a man of great statue had on
every hand six fingers and on every foot
six toes four and 20 in number and he
was he also was born to the
Giant and when he defiled Israel
Jonathan the son of Shemia the brother
of David slew him these four were born
of the Giants and gath and fell by the
hand of David and by the hand of his
servants oh so the giant like goath was
9 feet n in and he had three other
brothers but other scripture will let
you know there was a whole lot of giants
in the
land well they start at six feet at 7t I
don't know but uh these are the Giants
on this side of the
flood but that's all I have to say thank
you guest call for that answer sister so
yeah so her question uh for today the
people of of today will we call them
that are extremely tall like 7 feet and
up are they Giants would you consider
them Giants
the people of
today yes like they had a wrestler
called Andre the Giant right
right
so yes
sir okay sister Deborah next question
yes and her last question is was Noah
and his family considered
unclean even though he and his family
found Grace With God considering they
went in two by two I do understand they
were the only people
left yeah the two by two uh even though
they were
unclean they were alive animals even
though they were classified as unclean
so being among the unclean animals
didn't make Noah and his family unclean
but if any of those animals had
died and and Noah anybody in his family
had touched
them that would have made them unclean
and they would had to do what they had
to do to be made clean again by keeping
the Commandment of God that he told him
to keep to be made clean again and and
it's obvious you couldn't eat none other
none of the unclean animals because that
would make you unclean as well but as
long as they alive you can have them as
a pet and everything it's it's when they
die the caucus you know so I I think uh
that's in um Leviticus 11 where it talk
about the carcus right you know can I
weigh in yeah yeah the person asked the
question they was asking let asking in
another light okay they were saying with
no them unclean because they came two by
two no of them didn't come two by two it
was eight
four males and they
female that unclean 2 by two was
strictly about to animals
okay but they think but but the but the
drift of the question was because it
said no and his wife and his sons and
they wife they two by two was they
unclean
clean okay yeah no they wer unclean they
weren animals they was
man thank you
that's right and and uh can we read that
Genesis 7 read Genesis 7 one and
two Genesis 7 and 1 and two yes
sir the Lord said unto Noah Come Thou in
all thy house in thee AR for thee have I
seen righteous before me in this
generation of every clean Beast Thou
shalt take of thee by
the male and his female and other Beast
that are not clean by tooth the male and
his female so like the guest call and
Jerome was pointing out we talking Beast
right here this is not talking about
Noah and his wife at wife and his
children and their their wives right
hope that that answers your question and
sister Deborah will'll move on to the
next question yes moving on uh TX Domino
ask you to explain Romans 10:
1-14 uh TX Domino says I'm sure you guys
know the verses no need to read them all
but this is the place where today's
modern Christians go to say you don't
have to keep the law and all you have to
do is believe in God and your save I
know is not
true okay so we can go to that Romans 10
and we'll give it to the guest call and
let him deal with it from what verses he
would want to deal with it from gu
calling well go go and read a little bit
of it okay start at the
top Brethren my heart's desire and
prayer to God for is Israel is that they
might be saved for I bear them record
that they have a Zeal of God but not
according to knowledge for they being
even of God's righteousness and going
about to establish their own
righteousness have not submitted
themselves unto the righteousness of God
for Christ is the end of the law for
righteousness to everyone that
believeth for Moses describes the
righteousness which is of the law that
the man which doeth those things shall
live by
them but the righteous which
is let let's break in we ain't going to
do all that let's break into it show you
where the L Lord at Christ ended go to
Hebrews the 10th
chapter read one verse and then skip
down to four and
continue Hebrews
10 Hebrews
10 for the law having a shadow good
things to come and of the very image of
the things can never with those
sacrifices what they offer year by year
continually make the com there unto
perfect now what it start out it said
the law didn't it right that let us know
that this law is animal sacrifice so why
couldn't they make the uh uh uh uh
people that keep it perfect skip down to
verse four and read it for it is not
possible that the blood of bulls and of
ghost should take away sins
now go ahead and read wherefore when he
cometh into the world he says sacrifice
and offerings thou wouldest not but a
body thou prepared me and burn
offer he
reading keep reading and burn offerings
and sacrifices for sin thou has no
pleasure then said I lo I come in the
volume of the book it is written of me
to do thy will oh
God uhuh above when he says sacrifice
and offerings and burnt offerings and
offering for sin thou wouldest not
neither H has pleasure therein which I
offered by the
law now that's the law of an's
sacrifice but keep
reading then said he lo I come to do thy
will oh God he taketh away the first
that he may establish the second
by the which will we are Sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for
all okay now so when that happened what
happened to the law of animal sacrifice
skip down and read Verse
18 now where remission of these is there
is no more offering for
sin so now the law that was terminated
was the law of animal sacrifice
that was a temporary law and why did you
have animal sacrifice go to Galatians
the 19th Chapter I mean the third
chapter and read verse
19 wherefore then serve the
Lord wherefore then sered the law it was
added because of trans ression to the
seed should come to whom the promise was
made and it was ordained by angels in
the hand of a
mediator now that seed that came that
the promise was made was Jesus so now
this law was added because of sin and it
was only supposed to be be there until
the one that the promise was made which
was Jesus now what is sin First
Timothy what is it first Timothy uh uh
joh what three and
four and four go and read what Sin
is whosoever committeth Sin
transgresseth also the law for sin is
the transgression of the
law so that's what sin is the
transgression of the law so now if you
terminate the law if Jesus had
terminated the law then he would have
terminated sin too cuz you you ain't got
nothing to break right
nothing because it's written you know
where there is no law sin is not is not
imputed
right so now people break God's
commandment then God turn around and
said because the wage of sin is
death so in order to keep from killing
man he replaced him with animal
sacrifice so when a man sinned against
God he had to kill an animal right but
it couldn't make you perfect in other
words you couldn't get salvation through
killing animals so Jesus came and when
he died that killed animal sacrifice
that's why the veil of the temple rip
from top to
bottom there were no more animal
sacrifice for sin but you still had to
keep the law let me show you because
because sin is the transgression of the
law now go into Hebrews uh the 10 and
Skip Skip right on down where do it say
if you sin willfully
26 read
26 10 and 26 go ahead but if we sin
willfully after that we have received
the knowledge of the truth there madeth
no more sacrifice for
sins but a certain fearful looking forth
judgment and fiery indignation which
shall Devour the
adversaries now that mean if you break
God's Commandments
intentionally he remind you that there
ain't no more sacrifices for sin the
animal ain't going to die no more for
you and Jesus ain't going to die no more
for you so you going to die for yourself
the eternal life the Lake of
Fire you can't terminate the law the law
is there if you're going to get into the
father's Kingdom you have to go through
the law no matter what Paul's writing
look like that's why Paul the Lord told
you uh preter to warn you about Paul's
writing plus again too Paul was writing
to the Corinthian the Corinthian was
Gentile they didn't keep nothing they
had their own laws like Jupiter and Mars
and all that we're going to read one
more thing let you know that if you
don't keep the law you ain't going to
get into the father's Kingdom let's go
to
Revelation 22nd chapter
and read verse 14 and
15 revelation 22 verse 14-
15 read it when you get
there blessed are they that do his
Commandments that they might have right
to the tree of life and may enter in
through the gates into the city forth
out our dogs and Sorcerers and hor MERS
and murderers and idolators and whoo
soever loveth and maketh a
lie do if you want to get into that City
that New Jerusalem that's coming down
from heaven then you got to be somebody
that do God's commandments so if you
don't keep the Commandments you ain't
going to be in the good side of that
City you goingon to be in the Lake of
Fire that's all I have to say about
that yeah the law a made Paul told you
the law ain't made void through faith he
told you we established the law right
that is correct thank you guest caller
and brother Jerome for the addon we will
continue to move on sister Deborah next
yes moving okay moving on Miss way ask
in 1 Timothy 6 verse 20 to explain this
scripture and give an
example so we G to go to that first
Timothy 6 verse 20 and we'll open
yes go ahead and read it when you get
there brother uh
tanzel oh Timothy keep that which is
committed to thy trust avoiding profane
and vain babbling in opposition of
science falsely
socalled read read
21 which son professing have error
concerning the faith and Grace be with
thee amen
open to the
panel yeah when you look at this this
oppositions of science falsely
so-called and avoid profane and vain
babblings you know just stick with the
word of God stick with the word of God
stay on the
line all this other stuff that they that
people come with stay with the word of
God it will lead you right into
salvation if you endure
it so all these profane and vain
babblings don't deal with them yeah can
you give an example brother
Dre guess
caller let's go to Revelation 20th
chapter this is the best example you can
get yes sir Revelation chapter
Revelation
uhhuh and we going to read the uh start
at verse
11 and I saw a great white throne and
him that sat on it from whose face of
the earth and the heavens fled away and
there was found no place for them and I
saw the dead small and great stand
before God and the books were open and
and another book was open which is The
Book of Life and the they were judge out
of those things which were written in
the books according to their
works so now you going to be judged
according to the things that is written
in this book according to your works so
now anything that you talk about that's
not in this book or discuss that's not
in this book is
vain
B that's all I have to say that is right
because many voices out here telling you
you don't have to keep what's in this
book it's nail to the cross that is a
lie Paul said it in Romans 6 and one
let's let's go read that Romans 6 and
start at verse
one this is an example as well of of
people just you know they'll read one
thing and think they don't have to do
nothing else go ahead Romans 6
and Romans 6 and one go ahead yeah what
shall we say then shall we continue in
sin that Grace May abound and what is
sin we just read it in First John 3 and4
sin is the transgression of the law
shall we continue transgressing the law
of God
that Grace May abound verse two go
ahead God forbid how shall we that are
dead to sin live any longer therein and
if you continue to read that it lets you
know you buried with him in baptism
that's how you in sin and you raised to
walk in the newness of Life go ahead and
read brother go
ahead know ye not that so many of us as
we're baptized into Jesus Christ we're
baptized into his death
therefore we are buried with them by
baptism unto death like as Christ was
raised up from the dead by the glory of
the father even so we also shall walk in
newness of life and that's right so we
walk in the word of God by the spirit of
God which is his
word so I I hope that that helps can I
get can can I add one more
um Timothy uh where he talk about he
shall judge the quick and the dead at
his appearing and they think that
happened before then so that's that
ain't sound Doctrine and the Lord said
don't give heed to false Doctrine you
the false Doctrine don't tell us that
you gonna be judged as soon as you die
on Judgment day and you know or nothing
like that so that's all I got to say
thank you for that brother Jerome and
guest caller sister Deborah time
check yes the time is
8:51 Barbara still
says go ahead
sis all right
um I'm trying to find her I lost her
let's see here where is
she okay uh Barbara steel says does this
say anywhere in the Bible that you can't
eat certain Seafood because they are
they are bottom
eaters okay we gonna open that up to the
panel open to the panel is there
anywhere that say we can't eat any sea
food because they Bottom
Feeders no it don't say that in the
Bible for the seafood is concerned the
Lord give you one thing they have to
have fs and scales yeah
right River or anything else have
nothing to do with bottom fetus that's
somebody else's
addition that's
right and and you can read about that in
Leviticus 11 the fins and scales that's
what it
says verse 9 and 10 yes thank you for
that we hope that that helps and we'll
move move on to the next question sister
Deborah yes I
chuck woo
Amar uh asked which scriptures do I
present to my uncles and the elders in
my Village regarding not praying and
burning stuff over my late mom's
belongings and money over her grave
during her funeral
good question uh open to the
panel I'd say
um Deuteronomy 18 let's go to
Deuteronomy 18 and take a look at
that Deuteronomy 18 and uh
pick it up at verse n and go ahead and
read it
brother when thou I come into the land
which the Lord thy God give thou shall
not learn to do after the abomination of
those
Nations there should not be found among
you any of one that maketh his son or
his daughter to pass through the
fire or that use divination or an
observer of time or enchanter or witch
so all these things right here this
devation is when they pour out Libations
and call on the ancestor spirits to rise
up and just like what happened when when
Saul sought for Samuel by a familiar
spirit this is the same thing that's
happening in your village right and you
could share with them this but keep
going brother go ahead read some more or
a charmer or consulter with familiar
spirits or a wizard or
Necromancer uhhuh all that do these
things are an Abomination unto the Lord
and because of these Abominations the
Lord thy God doth drive them out before
thee that's right so the Lord don't want
us to do these things and the Lord said
he did not suffer us to do these things
so read verse 14 and 15 brother go ahead
for these nations with thou sh possess
hearken un hearken unto observers of
times and unto
divers but as for thee the Lord thy God
have not suffered thee to do so yeah you
don't you know this is something that
you don't do pouring out Libations and
calling on your ancestors and whatever
else they're doing that's against that
the Lord did not suffer you to do that
what else does it say verse
15 the Lord thy God will raise up unto
thee a prophet from the midst of thee
thy brother like unto me unto him ye
shall
hearken that's right so we got the word
of God that's what we hearken on
to word of God and informs us on how we
should live and what we should do right
so if anybody else would like to add if
not we'll move on we probably got time
for one or two more questions sister de
yes this uh person you're answering uh
the question because his second question
or their second question is which
scriptures do I show my uncle about
familiar spirits and and that it is
wrong in the sight of God so you talk
about that brother
Dre yeah we just we just read one of
them right you know uh let's go to
Leviticus
20 Leviticus
20 and uh
let's pick it up at
um let's pick it up at at
uh verse one read verse
one and the
Lord and the Lord spake unto Moses
saying go ahead again thou shal save the
children of Israel whosoever ye be of
the children of Israel or of a stranger
that sourn in Israel that giveth any of
his sea unto mole he shall surely be put
to death and the people of the land
shall Stone them with
stones skip down to verse five
brother then I will set my face against
that man and against his family and will
cut him off and all that go whing after
him to commit whoredom and with mole
from among their people uhhuh and the
soul that turth after such as half half
familiar spirits and after Wizards to go
a whing after them I will even set my
face against that soul and will cut him
off from among his people go ahead
sanctify yourselves therefore and be ye
holy for I am the Lord your
God that's right so this right here is
letting you know that the Lord do not
like that and we do that yeah he read it
earlier too like he was saying that 1
Chronicles 10 verse3 where he says Saul
he he says Saul died for his
transgression which he committed against
the Lord even against the word of the
Lord which he kept not and also for
asking counsel of one that had a
familiar Spirit to inquire of it
yeah absolutely uh sister Deborah time
check yes the time is
859 okay so I guess that's the close we
like to thank everyone who sent in all
those great questions from around the
world we took joy in answering them and
pray that you were edified if you didn't
hear your question answer tonight
there's no need to resubmit your
question it will be answered in the
order that it was given and we will pick
up where we left off next week so please
join us for next week's Q&A and be
strengthened in the Lord Brother tanzel
close us
out Our Father which are in heaven
Hallowed be thy name thy kingdom come
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us of our debts as as we
forgive our debt TOs and lead us not
into temptation but Deliver Us from Evil
for thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever in Jesus name we
pray amen